RYAN PRESBREY

Miami, FL 33145 ryan@ryanpresbrey.com

Accomplished senior IT professional with over 15 years of expertise in various roles within a wide number of industries. Earned a reputation for being intellectually curious, and flexible. Regarded as collaborative with an innate ability to partner with diverse audiences. Known for having a high-level communication style that translates shared values to everyone in the organization. Respected for having an influential leadership and inspiring workstyle.

Work Experience

VIP WHITE GLOVE END USER SUPPORT & VIDEO CONFERENCING SUPPORT

Santander Bank, North America

JUNE 2022 – Current

Responsibilities

- Supported Board members and other C-Suite and Senior Level end users (as well as their admins) in the Miami office and remote.
 - Support level is VIP White-Glove level for all users.
- Supported Board meetings in the Board room as needed.
- Supported other C-Suite level conferences as needed.
- Regular day-to-day support for non-Exec users as needed onsite in Miami.

Key Accomplishments

• Helped migrate C-Suite level users from Alrwatch to Intune Mobile Management software.

MANAGER CUSTOMER SUPPORT

APTIM/CB&I

JANUARY 2016 – APRIL 2022

Responsibilities

- Managed IT Regional Services group for US and Canada operations.
- My team was the first line of support for all IT problems throughout the company.
- I provided VIP White-Glove Support for CEO, Presidents, and VPs of the company as the IT Manager.
 - Also served as final escalation point if issues arose with support staff on my team.
 - My local office (in DC/Alexandria VA) was the primary office for working directly with the US Government – as such the CEO, President and VPs would visit often.
 - Supported the Contracts Division (housed in my office) which went after jobs for the company to work on directly, and as such needed White-Glove treatment for any issues they had.

- Assisted with server admin roles prior to creation of Server/Infrastructure team.
 - Managing backup jobs and network share administration.
- Configured/managed Active Directory user account objects.
- Configured/managed support roles for mobile devices within MS Intune environment.
- Supported video conferencing using MS Teams software (95%), and CISCO WebEx (5%)
 - Company used MS Teams internally, and used MS Teams and CISCO WebEx externally with clients.

Key Accomplishments

- Managed IT Team that supported a user base of around 3,000 computer operators, and a couple extra thousand users that would need to use a computer only for training purposes periodically.
- Onboarded vendor to manage Helpdesk phone support.
- Onboarded vendor to manage asset deployment/recovery.
- Managed IT team through the ongoing changes brought on by COVID with minimal turnover.
- Managed IT team helping with deployment/support of assets to assist in working with GOHSEP project in Louisiana for DR cleanup.

CUSTOMER SUPPORT ANALYST

CB&I/The Shaw Group JULY 2011 – JAN 2016

Responsibilities

- Lead technician for US Northeast area.
- Provided on-hand support for multiple high-profile government projects based out of NY state.
- First line of support for White-Glove Support VIP members of the local office which housed the President and VPs of the Environmental Disaster Management Division of the company.
 - Role involved working with Senior Managers and VPs that would work with clients to win work, was first-line of support for their issues including direct contact for support bypassing Helpdesk system.
- Admin for McAfee Encryption database, creating accounts and resetting tokens as needed.
- Systems Admin support for US Northeast region.

Key Accomplishments

- Worked on an IT Team that supported a user base of around 3,000 computer operators, and a
 couple extra thousand users that would need to use a computer only for training purposes
 periodically.
- Transformed multi-million-dollar Brooklyn project site into a more functional IT site for multiple years and helped close down the site as the project ended.
- Lead technician for IT Support for the Hurricane Sandy cleanup project in NYC/NJ region.

OXY IT ANALYST

Occidental Petroleum

JANUARY 2011 – JUNE 2011

Responsibilities

- Deskside support for end users locally and remotely.
- Helped provide White-Glove Support for the VIP/Board staff as needed.
- Setup PCs for new hires and upgrades for existing end users.
- Worked on package deployment for the company, by installing/testing software and providing directive to engineering team to package and deploy.

Key Accomplishments

- Provided White-Glove Support treatment for CEO, Chairman, President, Vice President and other board members of the company including support in office and at CEO home.
- Launched Windows 7 deployment team to provide smooth roll-out corporate-wide, and provide ongoing support during upgrade transition.

GSS TECH

The Shaw Group FEB 2008 – NOV 2010

Responsibilities

- Lead technician on a 5-member team providing end user deskside support locally and remote throughout the US Northeast.
- Primary technician dispatched for White-Glove Support of VIP users in the local office which
 involved the President and VP of the Nuclear Division and the Environmental Disaster Recovery
 Division.
- Was also primarily dispatched for job sites support and configuration for high-end project support.
- Admin for the McAfee Encryption server database, creating accounts and resetting tokens.
- System admin support for Active Directory maintenance, and shared drive configurations.

Key Accomplishments

- Helped setup and support multiple high-profile government contract job sites.
- White-Glove Support for VIP end users throughout company, especially the President and VPs of the different divisions based out of local office.
- Configured and supported Nuclear Engineering PCs (which required special offline configurations and updates) for nuclear projects for the company built script to deploy profile in a timely manner rather than manual setup.

DESKTOP SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

Pharmacare

JUNE 2007 – FEB 2008

Responsibilities

- Provided local end user deskside support for users in the office and remotely.
- Provided telecom support for end users in the local office.
- Provided printer maintenance for end users in the local office.
- Configure and maintain user account information in the corporate Active Directory system.
- Created logon scripts for network drive mappings for end users.

Key Accomplishments

• Helped create logon scripts for the company to use in more efficient network drive mappings (at the time it was not being used).

PC/NETWORK TECHNICIAN

The Shaw Group SEPT 2006 – JUNE 2007

Responsibilities

- Provided deskside support for end users within the local offices.
- Helped setup new hire PCs and upgrade existing end users PCs.

DESKSIDE SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

DePuy Spine

JUNE 2005 – SEPT 2006

Responsibilities

- Setup PCs for new hires, and upgraded PCs for existing users.
- Responsible for asset management for the Corporate HQ office.
- Supported VIP-Support Helpdesk, with White-Glove Support treatment for all members of the board, especially the CEO of Johnson and Johnson.
 - Support involved a direct contact cell phone that all the board members had and would use when they had issues.
 - Support was expected promptly and as politely as possible.
- Backed up Team Lead, ensuring policies/procedures were followed by IT Staff.

Key Accomplishments

- Helped write backup/refresh policy and scripts that continued to be used by the company for multiple years after leaving.
- Provided White-Glove Support treatment for all members of the board and their staff.

Education

A.D. in Computer Science with a focus on Micro-Computing and Networking

A.D. in Computer Science with a focus on Computer Programming

CCRI - Warwick, RI

Skills

- Desktop Support (Windows, Mac, Linux)
 - Break/fix support for both hardware and software.
 - Upgrading existing machines, and deploying machines for new hires.
- Server Support
 - Break/fix support for both hardware and software.
 - Helped with new VM deployment for corporate servers.
- Mobile Device Support (MS Intune)
 - Break/fix support for software on devices.
 - Used MS Intune to deploy new profiles to devices and wipe devices for re-use or disposal.
- MS Office 365 Support
- AD Administration Support
 - Created user accounts, and security groups.
 - Helped write logon scripts for use.
- Managerial Experience
 - Managed a team of multiple technicians throughout US and Canada.
- Networking Support
 - o Deployment of network hardware, wire management.
 - o Hands-on support for Network technicians at remote project sites.
- Video Conferencing Support (MS Teams and CISCO WebEx)
 - Helped troubleshoot connection problems or other hardware issues with end users during meetings.
 - Helped setup and pre-configure hardware for MS Teams meetings and Town Halls.
- Scripting
 - Basic scripting support as needed.
- SCCM Packaging
 - Helped support MS SCCM software and server for Software packaging and deployment.
- White-Glove Support for VIP Users
 - o In multiple roles at different companies, I was the primary tech for White-Glove Support for the VIP members of the company.
 - This would involve the users having a direct line of contact to me when they had issues, and would require a quick SLA turnaround when contacted.

o I would also be the technician that handled their computer deployments/upgrades as needed, and would work with hardware vendors for support as needed.

Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-presbrey/
https://www.ryanpresbrey.com/